export const quizCategories = [
  {
    name: 'Japanese',
    questions: [
      {
        id: 1,
        question: 'What is the traditional Japanese garment called?',
        answers: ['Kimono', 'Hanbok', 'Cheongsam', 'Sari'],  
        correctAnswer: 'Kimono',
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: 'What is the Japanese tea ceremony called?',
        answers: ['Gonfu', 'Chado', 'Chai ', 'Matcha'],
        correctAnswer: 'Chado',
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: 'What is hanami, a popular springtime activity in Japan?',
        answers: ['Viewing cherry blossoms', 'Making paper cranes', 'Sword fighting', 'Tea ceremony'],
        correctAnswer: 'Viewing cherry blossoms',
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: 'What is shinto, and why is it significant in Japan?',
        answers: ['A type of martial arth', 'A traditional dress', 'An indigenous spirituality', 'A tea ritual'],
        correctAnswer: 'An indigenous spirituality',
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question: 'What is the significance of the Japanese garden?',
        answers: ['It represents a paradise garden', 'It is for growing food', 'It symbolizes harmony', 'For tea only'],
        correctAnswer: 'It symbolizes harmony',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: 'Chinese',
    questions: [
      {
        id: 1,
        question: 'What is the Chinese New Year, and when is it celebrated?',
        answers: ['November', 'December', 'January-February', 'March'],  
        correctAnswer: 'January-February',
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: 'What is the concept of yin and yang in Chinese philosophy?',
        answers: ['Seasons of the year', 'Balancing forces', ' Chinese cuisine', 'Martial arts style'],
        correctAnswer: 'Balancing forces',
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: 'What is feng shui?',
        answers: [' A martial art', 'An architectural style', 'Harmonizing spaces', 'A religious practice'],
        correctAnswer: 'Harmonizing spaces',
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: 'What is the importance of tea in Chinese culture?',
        answers: ['Only for festivals', 'Symbolizes hospitality', 'Used for decorations', 'Limited to elites'],
        correctAnswer: 'Symbolizes hospitality',
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question: 'What are the Chinese zodiac animals, and how are they significant?',
        answers: ['Represent months', 'For martial arts', 'Yearly cycle traits', 'Lucky charms only'],
        correctAnswer: 'Yearly cycle traits',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: 'Hindu',
    questions: [
      {
        id: 1,
        question: 'What is the holy text of Hinduism?',
        answers: ['Quran', 'Torah', 'Bible ', 'Vedas'],  
        correctAnswer: 'Vedas',
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: 'What is karma in Hindu belief?',
        answers: ['Law of justice', 'Cause and effect', 'Cycle of birth ', 'Path to salvation'],
        correctAnswer: 'Cause and effect',
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: 'Who are the principal deities in Hinduism?',
        answers: ['vishnu, Shiva, Brahma', 'Zeus, Hades, Poseidon ', 'Odin, Thor, Loki ', 'Ra, Osiris, Isis'],
        correctAnswer: 'Vishnu, Shiva, Brahma',
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: 'What is the significance of the river Ganges in Hindu culture?',
        answers: ['For transportation', 'Purifying bath', 'Fishing spot', 'A tea ritual'],
        correctAnswer: 'Purifying bath',
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question: 'What is Diwali, and why is it celebrated?',
        answers: [' Festival of Lights', 'End of Harvest', 'Start of Monsoon ', 'Commemorates ancestors'],
        correctAnswer: 'Festival of Lights',
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    name: 'Slavic',
    questions: [
      {
        id: 1,
        question: 'What is the Slavic festival of Maslenitsa?',
        answers: ['Festival of Flowers', 'New Years festival', 'End of winter celebration', 'Harvest festival'],  
        correctAnswer: 'End of winter celebration',
      },
      {
        id: 2,
        question: 'Who is Perun in Slavic mythology?',
        answers: ['God of Love', 'God of Thunder', 'God of Thunder ', 'God of Fire'],
        correctAnswer: 'God of Thunder',
      },
      {
        id: 3,
        question: '	What is kupala night traditionally associated with?',
        answers: ['Viewing cherry blossoms', ' Water and fire rituals', 'Wedding', 'Winter solstice'],
        correctAnswer: 'Water and fire rituals',
      },
      {
        id: 4,
        question: 'What is a popular Slavic folk instrument?',
        answers: ['Balalaika ', 'Shamisen ', 'Bagpipes ', 'Sitar'],
        correctAnswer: 'Balalaika',
      },
      {
        id: 5,
        question: 'What is the traditional Slavic dish called borscht made from?',
        answers: ['Carrots', 'Beets', 'Potatoes ', 'Turnips'],
        correctAnswer: 'Beets',
      },
    ],
  },
];
